52초 후에 자막 나옵니다...
Previously on Limitless...
It's about time you and me talked.
- Do you know who I am?
- Everybody says you're gonna be president soon.
But between me and you, I don't
even know if I'm gonna run.
The world needs to be willing to change.
And it takes leaders who are willing
to cut through the noise and play the game
- and win the game.
- And that's you?
I think so.
You belong to Mr. Morra now, which means
you belong to me.
When I'm on NZT, I can think
through all the different
- angles, every perspective.
- Then shouldn't you have known
that I was gonna shoot Casey? You texted me.
Yeah, I... I didn't think you'd shoot.
Lower your weapon.
But I did.
(low conversations)
♪
(hinges creaking)
죄송하지만 들여다 보겠습니다
Sorry, ma'am, gonna have
to take a quick peek.
상원의원께서 저기 아래에서
회견을 준비 중 입니다
The senator's giving a
speech a few blocks down.
상원의원이요?
Senator?
그가 무슨 입법을 상정을 해서
He, uh, holds office in one
of two legislative bodies
조국을 위해 뭔가 한다고 하네요
that make the laws for this country.
저도 상원의원을 알거든요
I know what a senator is.
좋은 하루 보내세요
Have a nice day, ma'am.
(trilling, chirping)
(lock clicks)
(door closes)
♪
의원님?
Sir?
준비가 되었습니다
They're ready for you.
Okay.
(applause, cheering)
(cheering, whistling)
Thank you.
감사합니다, 앉으세요
Thank you. Please, sit down.
전쟁이 그만 둔 시점에서는
You know, when the wars were done,
전투함을 고철로 방치를 안 했습니다
they didn't scrap this ship.
새로운 임무를 주었습니다
They found a new mission for her.
바로 용기가 이 배에게 새로운 생명을
The Intrepid was used as a recovery vessel
바로 불어 넣어 주었습니다
- EDDIE (to self): Piece of glass just caught the light.
- for the Gemini and Mercury...
저기 보이는 게 쌍안경이겠지
Could be someone with binoculars.
저는 고귀함을 다시 한번
I'd like to give the same
dignity to our veterans
전쟁 영웅들에게 드리고 싶습니다
that we gave to this ship.
누군가 나를 향해 조준을 한다
Someone's taking a shot at me.
3,300 야드 거리이다
Call it 3,300 yards.
역사 상 가장 긴 암살 거리다
That'd be the longest kill of all time.
난 많은 내 수발들을 고용...
I hire as many vets as I can...
NZT
NZT.
파이퍼다
Piper.
총을 쏘기 전에 숨을 고르겠지
She'll breathe out before she shoots,
그걸 노리는 거다
so let's think this through.
테이블은 아닐 꺼고
Not on the table, obviously.
내가 뛰어 넘은 면
I could jump out of the way.
의원 암살 실패로
__
나쁘진 않군
Not bad.
그러나 탄이 나에게 너무 깊게 스치면?
But what if the bullet just grazes me?
모라 상원의원 영웅적으로
__
살해에서 살아남다
Yeah.
이거야
That'll do.
(crowd shrieking, screaming)
(phone dings)
위층에서 보자고 불러
They need you upstairs right now.
나 역시 소식 들었어
BRIAN: I saw the news. Of course I did.
도시 전체가 모라 상원의원에게
The whole city was talking
about what happened
일어난 일에 시끄럽다
to Senator Morra.
저기 모인 회의는
Let's review all the ways
잘못 될 수 있다
this could go wrong.
제도드 샌즈씨, 브라이언 핀치입니다
Ah. Jarrod Sands, this is Brian Finch.
긴급 사건 고문으로써 근무를 하고 있습니다
He consults with us on priority cases.
샌즈씨는 상원의원 에드워드 모라
Mr. Sands is a security consultant
의 경호를 담당하고 계십니다
for Senator Edward Morra.
우리는 서로 압니다
Brian and I know each other.
저희는 비밀리에 만났죠
We are in a clandestine relationship.
의원님과 전
The senator and I
NZT로부터 면역주사를 주었죠
give him immunity from
the side effects of NZT
그 대가로 그가 저희에게 보고를 하는 데
in exchange for him reporting back to me
여기서 일어나는 모든 일이죠
on what you lot get up to.
그래서 그 동안...
That explains so...
이상했군요
so much.
지금 당장 체포 할까요?
Should we just arrest him now, then?
원한다면요
If you like.
아니면 구금 전에 아주 심문을 독하게 하죠
Or I could take care of him round the back.
물론 그렇게 한다고 해서 다 불지는 않을 꺼야
Okay, it's not in his best
interest to take that approach,
그러나 레베카가 한 건 하지
but Rebecca is wicked smart.
만약 그녀가 다 안다면?
What if she figures it out?
의원님께서는 직접 못 오신 점 미안해 하십니다
The senator's sorry he
can't be here personally.
제 팀에서 뭐든지 필요 하신 것 도와드립니다
Anything my team can do to assist you.
좋아요, 참 제가 주소를 하나 가지고 있는데
Great. We should also address the fact
브러이언과의 비밀 회동 장소입니다
that you are in a clandestine
relationship with Brian.
제 추측으로는 이미 NZT 면역주사를
I'm guessing you give him immunity
그 쪽에서 제공을 했겠죠
to NZT's side effects
그리고 스파이 짓을 했지요?
and he tells you what we're up to?
아니에요
That is so not true.
알고 있어
They know.
내가 차에 탄 순간 건물이 터질 꺼야
Once I'm in the car, nuke
the building from orbit.
그건 그렇다고 확신 할 수 있지
Yeah, it's the only way to be sure.
(explosion)
난 모든 상상을 다해 보았다
I imagined it all kinds of different ways.
저희가 직접 의원님을 만날 수 있나요?
Can we talk about Senator
Morra's eyes for a second?
죽이줘?
Amazing, right?
파래
Blue.
그러나 현실에서는 그는 날 무시를 했다
But what really happened was
Sands basically ignored me.
그리고 저주 메일에 대해 이야기 했다
And they talked about hate mail.
의원님은 항상 적들이 있으세요
Senator Morra has some powerful enemies
아주 다양한 종류이지요
from a few different conglomerates,
그러나 개인적으로 이런 경우가 처음입니다
but personally I'd be surprised
if they'd make a play for him.
현장에서 다른 증거는 있나요?
Was there any evidence at the scene?
저격범 장소에서 나온 증거는 달리 없고
Um, no evidence was found
at the sniper's nest,
저희가 유일하게 갖고 있는 정보는
and the only information we got
현장에서 경호를 섰단 경찰관들이
from the two security guards on the scene
저격범이라고 추정되는 한 여성의
was a basic description of the woman
인상 착의만 이야기가 나온 상태에요
who they think was the shooter, so...
그러나 그 정보에 대해서는 현재 대외비입니다
Yeah, unfortunately, we've
had to use private security.
저에게 있어서 이 일의 중요사항은
It's the best I can do
until the senator decides
의원님이 곧 대통령을 도전 하신다는 점이죠
whether he's gonna run for president.
저희가 호텔 모든 사람들을 심문 중입니다
We'll interview everyone
who works at the hotel.
여러분 감사합니다
Thank you, everyone.
의원님께서 노고에 감사하실 겁니다
The senator will be sincerely
grateful for your help.
레베카
- Rebecca?
- Mm-hmm?
얘기 좀 할까?
Can I have a word, please?
(sighs)
좀 어때?
How are you holding up?
괜찮아요
I'm all right.
Uh...
보일이 총을 먼저 쏜 것이 맞다네
Boyle was the one who
had to pull the trigger.
케이시와 데이트 중이었지?
But you were dating Casey
Rooks, were you not?
그러나 그리 심각한 문제가 아니라서
But it wasn't serious, so
that's why I never filled out
인사과에 보고를 올리진 않았습니다
the "Status of Relationship" HR form.
I...
위에서 이걸로 뭐라 하겠죠?
They're gonna make this
an issue, aren't they?
저 역시 공범이냐 마냐고
Like I was trying to hide something.
아니
No, they're not.
그 이유는 자네가 이걸 싸인 할꺼지
Because you're gonna sign the form now,
자네가 증명을 했고 네가 확인한 사항이 되지
you're gonna back-date it,
and I'll make it official.
왜 도와주시는 거죠?
Why would you do that?
자네는 나에게 진실을 말했잖아
Because you told me the truth.
그리고 내 생가엔 자네는 잘못한 게 없어
And I don't think you did anything wrong.
그의 행동은 온전히 그의 책임이지
Rook's actions were entirely his own.
이 서류 덕분에
The form is just a bunch of lawyers
변호사들만 안 짤리겠네
trying to save their asses.
감사합니다
Thank you.
아 그리고
Oh, please.
여기서 근무 한 이후 난 싱글이라네
I've been single ever
since I joined the Bureau.
그리고 나래도 여기서 잠을 안 잤겠나?
Do you think I haven't
slept with anyone here?
우린 늘 바뻐
We're busy.
우리 같은 사람들이 어떻게 사귀어?
How else are we supposed to meet people?
(elevator bell dings)
(sighs)
항상 눈은 정면에
Eyes front, mate.
카메라가 우릴 지켜봐
They got cameras in here.
모든 걸 다 말해주지
I'll tell you everything.
만약 이름이 나온다면 다 전해들을 꺼야
If we get a name, you'll have it right away.
전 메일 줄려고 했어요
I was gonna e-mail you.
15층 좀 눌러 줄래요?
Can you hit 15 for me, please?
제 친구들과 전 근래에 노는데
Some friends of mine lately,
we've been playing
아캄 공포라는 보드게임이에요
this board game called Arkham Horror.
이 게임을 말할 것 같으면
It's this cooperative thing
where you work together
사랑 대포로 괴물을 물리치는 거죠
to defeat the monsters
of the Lovecraft canon.
항상 4명이서 해요
We could always use a fourth.
아이구, 바쁘신 것 같아요
Oh, sorry, you're probably really busy.
항상 필사적으로 이야길 하죠
(quietly): You always
come off as so desperate.
야, 제임스?
Hey, James, you know what?
그 게임 꽤 흥미로 와
That actually sounds pretty awesome.
나에게 톡 줘
Just give me a text, okay?
잠시만 번호도 모르는데요
Oh, wait, I don't have your number.
이름이 나왔어
We've got a name.
의원님을 노리는 자는 파이퍼 버드야
The woman who tried to shoot
Mr. Morra is Piper Baird.
그럼 이미 알고 계신다는 얘기군요
So you already know who did it.
확실한 정보야
We're fairly certain.
그녀도 역시 의원님을 위해 일했지
Piper used to work for Mr. Morra.
그러나 그리 우호적이지 않았어
The parting of ways was not amicable.
약을 끊기러 들자 굉장히 화를 냈고
We supplied her with NZT
until she went a bit mad,
의원님이든 관련 된 자들
모두에게 두고 보자 했지
declared war on Mr. Morra and
anyone associated with him.
아마도 지금쯤 금단형상에 힘들게지
She's been a terrible pain, to be honest.
우리가 그녀를 찾아 낼 것이고 멈추게 해야지
We're gonna find her, and we're
gonna sort the problem out.
그러는 동안 너의 할 일은
But in the meantime,
your job is to make sure
FBI에서 절대 그녀를 알면 안 되지
that the FBI never learn
the name Piper Baird.
그러면 수사방해를 하란 소리에요?
So you want me to sabotage
the investigation?
FBI에서 우리보다 먼저 그녀를 찾으면
If the FBI finds this woman before we do,
그녀가 의원과 NZT에 대해 불꺼야
she can tie the senator to NZT.
의원님이 감옥에 가거나 법원에 스시면
Which means Mr. Morra goes to jail or flees.
너의 약 또한 더 이상 없다는 이야기지
Which means no more booster shots for you.
그럼 우리보다 그녀가 의원님을 노려도...
If she manages to get to Mr.
Morra before we get her...
약이 없는 거야
No more booster shots.
(bell dings)
(keyless lock beeps)
그녀를 우리가 찾지 않는다면
Until we have Piper Baird,
너 역시 의원님과 함께 인생 끝이야
your fate is tied to Senator Morra's.
그래서 너가 무얼 하던지
Do what you need to do
이 여잘 조심히 죽여야 해
to keep them far away from that woman.
♪
번역 By 그냥 봐
번역 포럼
Synced by emmasan
www.addic7ed.com
케이시가 한 일은 누구도
아닌 그 자신의 일이지
What happened with Casey
wasn't anybody's fault but his.
만약 누군가 레베카에게
덮어 씌우려고 한다면
If someone's trying to put it on Rebecca,
그 역시 어이없는 것처럼
that's almost as ridiculous
나에게도 누명을 씌우는 일이야
as somebody trying to put it on me.
보일은 아직도 화가 나있다
BRIAN: Boyle is still upset.
내가 그를 죽이자고 하지 않은 사람이거든
I told him he didn't need to kill Casey.
이 일에 대해 한동안 들을 것 같아
I'm guessing I'll be hearing
about it for a while.
그래서 난 한 귀로만 듣는 중이다
I paid attention with one ear
그러나 차로 이동 중에 한편에서
그녀에 대해 알아내는 것은
but mostly spent the drive
learning more about the woman
역시 보일도 눈치 못 채게 해야 한다니
I was supposed to be make
sure Boyle never found.
솔직히 난 암살범에 대한 지식은 없다
Now I don't know what a typical
assassin's background is,
그러나 확실한 것은 학위가
전혀 필요없지 않았을텐데
but I'm pretty sure it
doesn't involve a scholarship
존스 홉킨스에서 신경화학을 전공하고
to study neurochemistry at Johns Hopkins.
평범한 유아 시절과 우등생이었다는 점
Completely normal childhood,
good kid, great student,
그러나 그녀의 엄마 치매가 나빠진 것이
but when her mother's Alzheimer's got bad,
엄마를 챙기기 위해 학교를 그만 두고선
Piper dropped out of
school to take care of her.
그 후에는 전혀 정보가 없다
After that, there wasn't much about her.
그러다가 14개월 전부터 다르다
Not until 14 months ago, anyway.
남친이 잠을 자는 동안
칼에 찔러 사망한 것이다
Her boyfriend was stabbed to
death while he was asleep.
그녀 역시 같이 있었고 경찰이 오기 전에
Piper was in the apartment, but she ran
이미 그녀는 도중 중이다
before the police got there.
그녀는 용의선상 중 1순위다
She's their top suspect.
요원님?
(honking) Spelman?
도대체 왜 그래요?
What was that for?
내가 너에게 이야기 하는 동안
"전혀 듣고 있지 않았어"
You had that "zoned out"
look while I was talking.
(scoffs)
(distorted talking)
개인 경호팀이라...
private security...
여성의 키가 대략 160에서 170사이고
a woman between five four and five six
쇼핑 백 8개나 들고선 들어간다...
carried eight or so shopping
bags into the suite...
그러곤 현장에 증거를 전혀 안 남겼다...
didn't leave much behind
in the way of evidence...
분명 가져온 쇼핑백에 라이플을
분해해서 가져왔겠죠
A woman brought the rifle in
with a bunch of shopping bags,
그런데 나머진 아직 모른다는 거죠?
and we don't know anything else. That it?
다른 사람들은 "죄송해요 다시
한번 알려주세요" 라고들 하지
You know, that "I barely listen to
anything you say" recap thing you do?
정말 예의라곤
It's rude.
♪
객실에는 전혀 그녀의 증거라곤 하나도 없다
There was no evidence at all in the suite...
그녀는 대단하다...
Piper's thorough...
그러나 한가지를 자꾸 쳐다 보게 된다
But I couldn't stop staring at something.
그림에 최근에 덧칠한 흔적이 있다
There's fresh ink on this drawing.
아이라이너로 한 것 같다
Actually, I think it's eyeliner.
심지어 마른 상태이다
It's barely even dry.
약을 안 했다면 전혀 눈치
채기가 어려웠을 것 같다
I wouldn't have noticed it
if it wasn't for the NZT,
보아하니 의미가 있을텐데...
which I think is the point...
누군가 날 시험을 들게 한다
Someone's testing me.
바로 그녀다
That's Piper.
그녀도 약을 한 상태다
She's on NZT.
왜 레이저가 필요를 했을까?
Why does she need the laser?
왜 이리도 무모하게 하지?
Why risk tipping me off?
그녀도 역시 내가 약을 한 상태를 알텐데
She knew I'd have to be on
NZT to notice the painting.
하지만...
Unless...
점, 점, 선
Dot, dot, dash.
모르스 코드군
That's Morse code.
그녀가 나에게 메시지를 보내려 한다
She's sending me a message?
새미 디피트로를 찾으면
날 찾을 수 있다
__
너 괜찮아? 좀 창백해 보여
You okay, Finch? You look kind of pale.
괜찮아요
I'm okay.
다른 생각은 없어?
Any brilliant insights?
그러네요
Uh, yeah.
그녀는 분명히 발코니에서 쐈을 겁니다
The shooter apparently used the balcony.
자네는 정말이지 대단한 것 같아?
How did we even function
before you came along?
일단 다시 되돌아 가서
Okay, let's head back.
보안 카메라에서 나온
영상을 같이 보았으면 해
All right, I want you to
review the security footage.
만약 거기서도 그 대단한
통찰력을 준다면 말야
See if you have any more of
those... penetrating insights.
새미 디피트로를 찾으라고?
Find Sammy DiPietro?
한양에서 김서방 찾기나 마찬가지군
She might as well ask me to find Bigfoot.
♪
디피트로는 마피아와 연계가
된 조합회장이었다
DiPietro was a union leader
with ties to the Mafia.
70년대에 그는 사라졌다
He vanished in the '70s.
다들 죽었다고 보는데 아직 사체가 안 나타났다
Everyone assumes he's dead,
but no one's ever found the body.
근데 왜 그녀는 나와 대화를 하려 하지?
And why does Piper want
to talk to me, anyway?
저거 보이지?
Okay, you see that, right?
그녀는 뛰어나지만 완벽히 카메라에게서
Piper's good, but she
couldn't keep her face off
얼굴을 다 감추진 못하지
all the security footage.
저 영상들을 조금 바꾸어 놓는다면
You got to trim those frames out,
세미 디피트로에 대해서도 아무도
모르게 찾아 낼 수 있을 꺼야
and you got to find everything
you can about Sammy DiPietro.
이유는 모르지만 그녀가 시험 중인 거야
I don't know why, but Piper's testing you.
그녀가 그 아저씨를 찾으라고 하니 한번 찾아봐
And if she says you can find
DiPietro, then you can find him.
(exhales)
(tapping keyboard)
샌즈가 그랬잖아
You heard Sands, man.
선택의 기로가 없다고
You don't have a choice.
안다고
Yeah, I know.
단지...
It's just that...
FBI와 공존하는 것과 레베카를 배신하는 게...
working against the FBI,
betraying Rebecca...
매 순간마다 좀 더 쉬울 줄 알았는데
Every time I do that,
it gets a little bit easier.
핀치군을 믿지를 않는다는 게 맞아?
You sure you're not
slowly turning into Finch?
갑자기 색깔 놀이를 하고?
Building models with colored yarn?
이건 사실 도식표야
Actually... it's a diagram.
Mm.
무슨 말인지는 알아, 그는 어디에 있어?
But I see your point. Where is Brian?
뭔가 알아볼 게 있다고 했어
Said he was running down a hunch.
웃긴 건 이 사건에 집중을 안 보여
(whispers): For what it's worth,
he seems pretty off his game.
아마도 그에게 대한 당신의
예의에 반응을 하는 가보지
Well, maybe he's internalizing
your attitude towards him.
굉장히 섬세한 사람이야
He's very sensitive.
아냐, 우린 괜찮아
Nah, we're fine.
국장하곤 어때?
How'd it go with Naz?
좋았어, 단지...
All good. We just...
서류 정리를 할 게 있었어
We're finishing up some paperwork.
덕분에 조사할 시간이 있었지
I had some time to do some research.
여기 도식표를 보면
These represent
역사상 가장 긴 암살 거리야
the five longest confirmed
sniper shots of all time.
이건 영국군인데
The record belongs to a British officer
아프카니스탄에서 2,700 야드 였고
who served in Afghanistan: 2,700 yards.
그는 미식축구 경기장을 2개 이상 합친 거고
He beat second place by
a whole football field.
그리고 이 라인은 이번 사건의 기록인데
This represents the deck of the Intrepid
and the hotel where the shot was fired.
3,315 야드야
3,315 yards.
그녀가 역사상 가장 긴 거리를 앞지른 거야
She took a shot that would
have beaten the old record
축구장을 6개나 합친 거리지
by six football fields.
Wow.
상당한 거리인 거지
The round was standard.
분명히 일반적인 라이플일 텐데
It was fired from an off-the-shelf rifle.
다른 기술이 도왔을 리가 없지
There was no new technology.
아무도 그런 거리를 만들지 못해
Nobody could make that shot.
아니면 도움을 받았을지도 몰라
Well, maybe she had some help.
이런 경우처럼 무언가 도운 게 없다면
Can you think of anything
that would help someone
관연 이게 가능하다고 생각해?
do something that was otherwise impossible?
너의 생각엔 NZT복용을 한 암살범이란 소리군
You're thinking the sniper was on NZT.
아주 긴 거리야
It's a lot of red yarn.
근데 이 실은 브라이언만큼 정확하진 않지
Yeah, and your tape's not as clean
as the way Brian would do it.
"새미 디피트로를 찾아라"
"Find Sammy DiPietro."
처음에는 갈피를 못 잡지만
Sounded impossible at first,
but when you can plow
50년간 모든 서류를 살펴보면
through 50 years of files
in a couple of hours,
흥미로운 점들이 보이기 시작하지
interesting things can present themselves.
프릿츠 운더리히군요?
Fritz Wunderlich?
전 항상 좀 더 디트리치
You know, I was always
피셔-디스카수 타입을 좋아했죠
more of a Dietrich
Fischer-Dieskau man myself.
물론 독일 오페라하면 그죠
As far as German opera goes.
뭘 원하는 가?
What do you want, kid?
당신은 쟈니 "오페라" 벌라디씨 이죠
I know you're Johnny "Opera" Velardi.
당췌 무슨 소리지?
Hmm, what gave it away?
로티토 마피아 일원이시죠
I know you have ties to
the Lotito crime family.
헛소리구먼
Allegedly. Mmhmm.
난 은퇴한 트럭 운전수지
I'm just a retired truck driver.
저도 알아요
Mm, I know.
할배는 사체를 가지고 가신 적이 있죠
And you drove the truck
that carried the body
드럼 통 안의 새미 디피트로 사체죠
of Sammy DiPietro in a steel drum
그를 살해를 했고 숨겨둔 곳이죠
from where he was murdered
to where they stashed him.
15번씩이나 확인을 한 겁니다
Been questioned about it 15 different times.
자네 누군가?
Who are you?
연방 애로는 안 보여
(scoffs) You certainly
don't look like a Fed.
말하자면 길어요
It's a long story.
그저 지나가는 과객이라고 하죠
Let's just say I'm a concerned citizen.
그리고 할배가 죽이진 않았을 테죠
To be clear, I don't think you killed him.
사실 할뱌는 무엇을 가지고
In fact, you probably didn't even know
가신지도 모르셨을 테고요
what it was you were transporting.
그 날밤 어디로 가신 지만 알고 싶네요
I just want to know where you
drove the truck that night.
젊은이, 40년 전 일이야
Kid, that was 40 years ago.
어디로 운전을 했다고 안다고 해도
Even if I could remember
where I drove that truck,
왜 내가 불어야 해야 하지?
why would I start talking
after all this time? (zipper opens)
거절 하실 수 없는 것을 드릴 테니깐요
'Cause I'm gonna make you
an offer you can't refuse.
(scoffs)
불법이지만 절대 가질 순 없는 거죠
This is a bootleg that even
you don't have, Johnny.
할배는 몰랐겠지만 지난 20년 간
You didn't know it, but you were wire-tapped
FBI는 할배한테 도청을 했습니다
for almost 20 years by the FBI.
(soprano singing aria)
아내 분이세요
That's your wife.
부인이 애기 때인 아드님에게
노래를 불러주는 겁니다
She's singing to your
son when he was a baby.
아름답죠
It's beautiful.
푸치니이지
It's Puccini.
부인에게 생긴 일에 대해 유감스럽네요
I was sorry to read what happened to her.
제 이모도 백혈병이었죠
You know, my aunt had leukemia.
이건 원본입니다
That is the master copy,
그날 밤에 트럭을 어디로 간지만
and it is all yours if you just tell me
말해 주심 다 드립니다
where you drove the truck that night.
아무도 우리 대화를 모를 겁니다
No one will ever know we talked.
♪
그날 밤 그 할배가 운전해서 온 장소가
The night Johnny "Opera" delivered his truck
여기 미스테리한 장소이다
with its mysterious cargo, he came here.
새로이 콘트리트를 부었다고 했다
He said a new concrete
floor had been poured.
그래서 여기 어딘가에 그의
(door closes) So somewhere
in all this concrete
사체가 누워 있을 것이다
lies the body of Sammy DiPietro.
그러나 여기 온 이유는 하나다
But that's not why I'm here.
확실히 여긴 파이퍼의 은닉장소로 보인다
Obviously this is where Piper's been hiding,
어디에 있는 거지?
but where is she?
브라이언, 너는 확실히 서있는 게 맞니?
__
♪
단지 한 발짝만 움직이면!
__
Mom?!
Dad?!
(Dennis laughs)
아들아!
Hey! Brian!
Hi!
안녕하세요
Hi.
뭐 다른 일은 없죠?
Is everything okay here, guys?
응, 와서 앉아
Of course. Come, sit.
새 여친에 대해 막 알아가던 참이야
We're just getting to
know your new girlfriend.
♪
자기야, 왜 그래?
What's wrong, Brian?
아냐, 암것도...
Nothing, uh, it's just...
봐서 너무 놀랬어
I'm surprised to see you.
여기서
Here.
가족이랑 말이지
With my family.
여친이 생긴 걸 왜 이야기 안 한거니?
How could you not tell us
that you had a girlfriend?
그가 정성 들여서 저흴 소개를 준비했어요
Uh, he had this whole
elaborate plan to introduce us.
제가 기다리기가 지루하더라고요
I just... kind of got tired of waiting.
저 녀석이 좀 고집스러운 면이 있지
Yes, well, our Brian likes
to do things in his own way.
지 멋대로고
On his own time.
괜찮아요, 그가 이해를 하는 듯 보이네요
That's okay, I-I think I got
him pretty well figured out.
파이퍼가 너희 첫 데이트 얘기를 하더라고
Piper was just telling
us about your first date.
그런가요?
- Oh, yeah?
- (timer beeps)
너희 모두 저녁을 먹고 가겠지
Ah. Oh, well, I assume you're
both gonna stay for dinner.
엄마, 아직 잘 모르겠네요
Oh... (chuckles) I don't know yet, Mom.
파이퍼...
Piper...
현관에서 좀 얘기 할까?
quick word on the porch, please?
금방 돌아오죠
BRIAN: Thanks, we'll be right back.
아범님과 당신 사이에 긴장감이 느껴져요
I was sensing some tension
between you and your dad.
무슨 짓을 한 거죠?
What did you do?
잘 들어요, 가족은 이것과 상관없어요
Listen to me, my family
is not a part of this.
그런 소리가 어디에 있어요
You can't really believe that.
모라와 함께 하는 순간 다 관계가 있죠
Not after being around Morra for this long.
다른 자들에게 말 안 했죠?
Did you tell anyone I was here?
긴장 풀어요, 진실을 말하는지 알아야 해요
Relax, I just need to know
if you're telling the truth.
샌즈가 여기에 대해 아나요?
Does Sands know where I am right now?
아뇨
No.
(slow, rhythmic heartbeat)
전 당신을 위협하러 온 것이 아니에요
I'm not here to threaten you.
부모님들도 마찬가지에요
I'm not gonna hurt your parents.
시간에 쫓기는 중이에요
I just don't have much time.
전 모라가 아는 만큼
I had to learn everything I could
당신에 대해 알았어야 해요
about the person Morra is working with.
무엇을 배웠죠?
Yeah? What did you learn?
중산층 가정답게 이해를 구해야 하고
Classic middle child, which
explains your need for approval.
반면에 당신은 공포를 늘 느끼고 있죠
On the other hand, your fears of living up
당신이 하는 일이 가져올 사태에
대비하여 가족을 구하고 싶고요
to your successful older
siblings caused you to rebel
거절 할 수 없는 지경이란 점이죠
and reject mainstream success.
"재분화 된 쌍둥이죠"
"Resorbed Twin."
그게 단지 멋져서 지은 밴드 이름은 아니겠죠?
You really thought that
was a reasonable band name?
가장 중요하게 제가 당신에 대해
The most important thing I learned is
배운 점은 당신은 사랑에 둘러싸여
살고 있다는 점이죠
that you grew up surrounded
by love and support,
그게 바로 윤리적으로 강한 힘이죠
which suggests a strong moral framework.
왜 윤리적으로 강한 것에 관심을 두죠?
Why do you care if I have
a strong moral framework?
그리고 얼마나 이걸 준비를 한 거죠?
And how long were you in there for?
7분이요
Seven minutes.
모라만이 유일한 목적이에요
And I care because I know how Morra works.
그는 사람을 타락 시킬 줄 아는 자이죠
He has a way of corrupting good people.
당신도 그 중 하나죠
You're one of them.
저 역시 마찬가지였죠
Same way I was.
당신의 남친을 죽인 것이 의원의 탓이다?
So it's his fault that you
killed your boyfriend?
브라이언, 전 그를 안 죽였어요
I didn't kill my boyfriend, Brian.
모라가 그랬죠
Morra did.
아님 그의 사람들이죠
Or his people.
왜 그들이 그렇게 했죠?
And why would they do that?
논문을 쓰고 있을 때 접근을 했죠
He came to me when I was
writing my dissertation.
제 논문을 읽었던 것 같아요
I guess he'd read some of my work.
저에게 NZT를 얘기했죠
He told me about NZT,
효과를 경감화 시키는 지 말이죠
how he was trying to
alleviate the side effects
제가 같이 일한다면 할 수 있다고요
and how, if I could help him do it,
약이 엄마를 살릴 수 있다고요
the pill might help my mom.
당신이 효소를 개발한 거죠?
You invented the enzyme?
저랑 다른 사람들이요
Well, me and some other people.
그들이 누군지는 몰라요
I don't know who they are.
의원이 다 떨어놓고선 진행을 했죠
Morra kept us all separate.
그에게는 능력이...
He has this way of...
있는데 사람들에게 좋은 사람처럼 굴죠
making people think he's a good person.
사실 그가 몰래 하는 일에는
How, no matter what he does,
다른 속셈이 있는데 말이죠
it's all for some greater good.
어느 날, 전 그에 대해 의심을 했죠
And one day, I stopped believing
그랬더니 그의 말은 다 거짓이었어요
that it was about anything other than him.
그래서 제가 약들과 효소를 훔쳤는데...
So I stole a supply of NZT and the enzyme...
전 남친을 죽인 죄로 앙갚음을 하려 해요
and he framed me for
killing Colin as retribution.
그래서 전 그를 멈추어야
하겠다고 생각한 거죠
That's when I decided
he needs to be stopped.
이미 떨어지기 시작했군요
You're running out.
약들이나 아님 효소, 둘 다 던지요
Of NZT, or the enzyme, or both.
그래서 의원이 굉장히 필사적으로
You know, something about the attempt
되찾길 원하는 거구요
on Morra seemed desperate.
그는 현재 약을 복용을 한 사람 중
He has been on NZT longer
가장 긴 사람일 겁니다
than any human being alive.
그이게 다가온다고 미리 생각 했을 테죠
You had to know that he
would see that coming.
아니면 기다릴 수가 없었거나
But you couldn't wait any longer
어쩌면 기회가 영영 안 올 수도 있죠
or you might miss your one shot forever.
효소를 만드는 데 거의 마쳐가요
I'm close to replicating the enzyme,
제가 그렇게 한다면 그는 더 이상
and when I get there, his
plan to keep NZT to himself,
그 약의 원천 제공자가 안 될 테고
to keep it from doing all the good
아시다시피 그렇게...
you and I know it could...
족쇄에서 벗어나죠
that's all over.
위협이었다면 전 이미 죽었겠죠
If you saw me as a threat,
I'd be dead already,
그럼 뭐죠?
so what is this?
추측한데 저에게서 원하는 것이 있죠?
Presumably, you want something from me.
저처럼 그의 똘마니 중 하나죠
You're under his thumb, same way I was.
그는 제 삶을 송두리째 가져갔어요
He took everything from
my life that mattered.
당신도 마찬가지죠, 잘 알 텐데요
He'll do the same to you, trust me.
유일한 탈출구가 있어요
There's only one way out.
그게 뭐죠?
What is that?
절 도와서 에디 모라를 죽이는 거죠
You're going to help me kill Eddie Morra.
어디 가시는 거죠?
Where are you going?
그냥 갈 순 없잖아요
I can't just leave.
어머님께서 고기 로프를 하셨죠
Your mom made meat loaf.
REPORTER (on TV):
Insiders say they have no idea...
밤새도록 난 결론을 내릴 수 없다
BRIAN: At the end of the night,
I was no closer to knowing
그녀가 단지 불만으로 이 일을 했다는 걸
if Piper was a disgruntled former operative
아님 그들의 희생자일 수도
or a victim of Morra and Sands.
만약 효소를 만드는 데에 성공을 거진 했다면
If she was close to making that enzyme,
그녀는 다른 원천 제공자가 될 수 있다
she could be another source
for the booster shot.
그녀만이 의원에게서 풀어 줄 수 있는 사람이다
She could get me free of the senator.
오늘 그녀를 보았음, 만나요
__
당신만 말고 그도요
_
제가 새로운 동업자 되죠
EDDIE: I'll co-sponsor a new one,
원하는 것에 40%을 떼어주죠
give you 40% of whatever you want,
아무것도 없는 것보다 나아요, 그죠?
which is better than 100% of nothing. Okay?
다이엔에게 안부 전해줘요
Well, give my best to Diane.
(phone beeps off)
그는 바람을 피는 중이야
He's cheating on his wife.
내가 다이엔을 끌어들여서
I bring up Diane,
순순히 말을 듣도록 해야겠어
makes him a little more pliable.
그녀의 전 남친을 죽이셨나요?
Did you kill Piper Baird's boyfriend?
(sighs)
그녀가 찾아냈군, 그럴 줄 알았지
She found you. I thought she might.
그녀가 뭘 원하지?
What does she want?
나에게 오도록 이용을 한다고 했어?
She wants to use you to get to me?
당신이 죽였나 고요?
Did you kill her boyfriend?
우리가 하는 일은...
The work we do...
당장은 어둠 속에 진행을 하지
it's in the shadows, for now.
그렇게 해야 하니 어둠 속에서 지휘를 하지
I operate in the dark because I have to.
제가 하는 일에 불법적인
부분은 있다고 할 수 있어
Look, I'll defend what we're
building to my dying breath,
그러나 살인만큼은 하지 않아
but I wouldn't kill anyone
하지만 날 죽이겠다고 한다면
이야기가 달라지지
unless they were threatening
to do the same thing to me.
답변이신가요?
Is that an answer?
난 아니야, 그녀가 그런 거지
I didn't kill him. She did.
(exhales)
그녀는 한때 유능했지만
Piper Baird is brilliant,
지금은 충치지
but she is tortured.
거짓말쟁이에다가
And she's a liar.
내가 그녀를 내쫓은 후
After I cut her off,
내 연구소 중 한곳에 침입을 해서
she broke into one of my R&D facilities
일년치의 효소를 들고 튀었어
and stole a year's supply of the enzyme.
이제 떨어지자 맹목적으로 달려들지
And now she's running
out and she's desperate.
자네 입장에서는 이해가 돼
You're torn; I understand.
잘 설득을 시키지는 여자지
She's very convincing.
브라이언, 그녀는 자네를 도울 수 없어
But she can't help you, Brian.
효소를 어떻게 만드는 방법을 몰라
She doesn't know how to make the enzyme.
한편으로 자네는 다행이지
In a way, you're lucky,
이런 특수한 상황에서
because in this situation,
실용적인 선택을 할 수 있는 기회가 생겼지
the right choice is the pragmatic choice.
이런 기회가 흔치 않아
And those don't come along every day.
그녀가 먼저 우리에게 지지 않겠지
Piper's not done with any of us yet.
그래서 할 일이 남은 거야
One thing left for you to do.
약을 현명하게 사용해
(scoffs) And use the NZT wisely.
이제는 저에 대해 좀 아시지 않나요?
Don't you two know me
better than that by now?
난 이 일에 더 이상 말을 아끼지
I'm not going to mean-mug
you on this one, Brian.
이제는 우리 일원이잖아
You know full well how this works.
자네는 선택의 기로가 없고 이 일은
You're due another shot soon
자네가 희생을 해야 하는 부분이지
and this needs to happen.
그녀는 우리 턱밑에 왔어
Piper came after us.
그리고 자네만이 속히 없애는 방법이지
And now you're the
fastest way to get to her.
들어봐...
Listen, son...
우리가 세우려는 제국을 생각해
defend what we're building, Brian.
그 일을 다 하면
When you're done,
강에다 던지게
chuck it in the river.
추적이 안돼
It's untraceable.
(exhales)
어디에 있다 온 거야?
Where the hell have you been?
보일과 난 오전 내내 찾았어
Boyle and I have been
trying you all morning.
미안, 일이 있었어
Yeah, sorry. I had stuff to do.
간밤에 이상한 정보가 나왔어
We got an anonymous tip in
the middle of the night.
목격자의 진술과 일치하는
A woman matching the description
용의자가 버려진 건물에
the security guards gave you
있다는 첩보였지
was found hiding in an
abandoned building uptown.
SWAT에서 방금 데려왔어
SWAT just picked her up.
보일이 심문 중이야
Boyle's questioning her now.
저건 누구야?
Who's that?
이름이 브렌디 조 호킨스이고
Her name is Brandy Jo Hawkins.
방금 암살 시도를 했다고 불었어
She just confessed to
shooting Senator Morra.
저 여자? 암살범이라고?
BRIAN: That woman? Brandy Jo Hawkins?
당연히 그녀는 범인이 아니다
She obviously didn't shoot Senator Morra,
그러나 용의자처럼 확실히 보인다
but she makes a great suspect.
군에서 유일한 여성 스나이퍼 출신이다
She was one of the first
female snipers in the military.
이라크에서 이미 4명이나 죽인 기록이 있다
She had four confirmed kills in Iraq,
그런데 군대에서 내쫓아 내졌다
then got kicked out of the military
선임병을 폭행한 죄목이다
for hitting a superior officer.
그녀는 급진적인
She was an easy target to be radicalized
용의자로는 딱 이다
by a grass-roots militia.
그러나 그녀 역시 이유가 있을 것이다
The way she told it,
Brandy had means and motive.
이미 어떻게 진술을 할지 안다
She knew details.
마약상이 그녀에게 약을 주었다고 했다
She said a meth dealer gave her an NZT pill.
의원은 FBI가 그녀를 못 찾고 싶은 것이다
Senator Morra wants the FBI
to stop looking for Piper.
그렇게 하기 위해서라면?
Best way to do that?
다른 가짜 범인을 주는 방법이다
Give them a different shooter.
오직 신만이 그 이유를 알고 있겠지
God knows how he got that
poor woman to take the fall.
그들은 그들의 꼭두각시를 가진 셈이고
Okay, so Morra and Sands have their patsy.
그렇담 할 일이 하나인데 바로
That leaves one thing on their to-do list.
파이퍼를 제거 하는 것이다
Piper.
나보고 그녀를 죽이라 했다
They want me to kill her.
그녀는 같이 그들을 죽이자 했다
She wants me to kill them.
어느 편에 서야 하나?
Who do I side with?
왜 자꾸 고민을 하는데?
SWEATER BRIAN:
Why should you side with anyone?
굳이 살인을 해야 하나?
I mean, who says you have to commit murder?
그들이 원해
They do.
죽이라는 명령만 내린 셈이지
They didn't give me an
option of not killing anyone.
맞아
BADASS BRIAN: Exactly.
그러니 고민하지 말고 해버려
That's why there's not even a question here.
힘 있는 편에 서야지, 바보야
You dance with the one that brung ya.
당연 에디야
And that is Eddie.
파이퍼 말론 곧 효소를 만든다고 했어
Piper says she'll create the enzyme soon.
전 남친도 자기가 아니라고 했지
She says she didn't kill her boyfriend.
근데 넌 아는 게 없지
But you don't know.
이런 상황에 단지 너가
The only thing you do know
해야 하는 건 의원을 도와주는 일이야
is that Eddie Morra can help you.
그게 옳은 일이야
That's for certain.
난 한가지 확실히 아는 게 있지
REBECCA: I'm pretty sure about one thing.
넌 살인자가 아냐
You're not a killer.
그렇다고 볼 수 없지
SANDS: No one's a killer.
죽였다면 달라지는 거야
Not until they kill, that is.
그나저나 입고 있는 건 뭐야?
What are those things you're wearing?
다들 조용, 난 지금 심각하다고
All right, obviously I'm
having a hard time with this.
그래서 너희들이 나타난 것이고
That's why you all are showing up.
잠깐 조용히 생각을 할 수 있다면
So if I could just have
a little peace and quiet,
- 난 말이지...
- 실례합니다?
- I think that I...
- IKE: Excuse me?
왜 제가 여기에 온 건지는 모르지만
I'm not sure what I'm doing here,
이 옷을 입으면 너무 따가워요
but these things really make me itchy.
아이크, 여기로 오면 돼
BADASS BRIAN: Join Team Badass, Ike.
가죽 쟈켓이 기다리고 있어
You get cool leather jackets.
가죽이 제 스타일이긴 해요
Leather sticks to my skin.
알았다고!
All right, enough!
아들아, 너무 힘들게 가져 가는구나
DENNIS: Oh, you're making
this too hard, kid.
아무리 봐도 답이 없어요
There's no way out of this.
양자택일 밖에는요
I mean, one way or another,
한쪽은 원하지 않은데 해야만 하고
I'm gonna be forced to do
something that I can't.
다른 쪽은 안 하면 죽임을 당하죠
And if I don't, I'll die.
결국 부모님들도 위험에 빠지게 돼요
And it'll blow back on you guys.
- 누굴 믿어?
- 네?
- Who do you believe?
- What?
그게 먼저 결정을 해야 하는 부분이지
That's the first thing you're
gonna have to decide.
의원이 사이코인 살인자야?
Is Senator Morra a cold-blooded murderer,
아님 그녀가 정말 살인자일까?
or did Piper Baird kill her boyfriend?
넌 알 수가 없어
You're never gonna know,
그렇담 직감으로 결정해야 해
so you have to go with what you feel.
더 믿는 사람 편으로
Decide who you believe.
서서 싸워
Side with them.
그런 후에 생각을 하면 돼
And then you can really start thinking.
브렌디 조 호킨스 말로는
Brandy Jo Hawkins said
마약상으로부터 약을 받았다고 했지
she got NZT from a meth dealer.
그런 마약 상들이 그 약을
When's the last time someone below wholesale
마지막을 판 적이 언제지?
had a pill to sell?
Mm...
한 18개월 전? 왜?
Maybe 18 months? Why?
그녀의 진술은 이상해
Something's wrong with her story.
그녀의 혈액 반응 검사도
Her blood test confirmed
물론 복용을 했다고 나오지만
that she had NZT in her system,
그래서 다른 검사를 다 해보았는데
but I ran a full battery
뭔가가 나왔어
and something else came back, too.
그녀는 크러츠펠트 야곱 병을 가졌어
She has Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease.
치명적인데
It's fatal.
신체상태에 따라 굉장히 위험하지
It plays havoc with your coordination.
그런 상태임에도 불구하고
Yet she managed to get
herself into position,
암살을 하기 위해 위험을 무릅쓰며
take an impossible shot,
모든 카메라도 피한 용의자인데
and avoid every surveillance camera.
무언가 이상하게 맞지를 않아
So something's not sitting
right with you, either?
근데...
Yeah, well...
당시 범인은 너무 현명하게 일처릴 했지
It's... she was so smart along the way.
그런데 갑자기 나타났다!
Then, all of a sudden, bam! (snaps fingers)
이상한 첩보와 그녀가 진술을 하는
An anonymous tip, she's sitting
모든 상황들은 언뜻 맞지만
right in our lap, telling us everything.
너무 쉽게 풀려
It just seems too easy.
그리고 이거 봐
And you know what else?
그녀의 부모님 자택이
Her parents' house
2일 전만해도 강압적으로 차압 중인데
was in foreclosure up until two days ago,
우리가 그녀를 데려 오는 순간 이후에
right before we picked her up.
은행 측 실수라 정정을 해서 다 풀렸어
The bank settled, supposedly
an accounting error.
그래서 지금은 아무런 문제도 없어
Now it's theirs, free and clear.
그러면 집 빛을 문제로 그녀를 설득해서
Well, what if someone settled
the debt against her house
만약 그녀보고 진술을 부탁을 했다면
and in return, she confessed to a crime
심지어 하지도 않은 일을?
she didn't commit?
병 때문에 1년도 못 가서 죽을 테고
Because of her disease, she'll
be dead within the year.
그렇기에 그녀 역시 뭔가를 남길 수 있지
This way, she gets to leave something
특히 부모님을 위한다면
for her family.
만약 그녀가 누명을 받아들인다면
If she's taking a fall...
누구를 위한 것일까?
who's it for?
왜 복용까지 해서 의원을 노린 거지?
And why would someone on NZT
be targeting Senator Morra?
♪
절 믿었군요?
So, you believe me?
믿었어요
Yeah, I believe you.
전 믿기 힘들었어요
I don't know if I trust you.
약속한대로 무장을 안 하고 왔어요
PIPER: I came unarmed, just like you asked.
의원은 당신이 정신문제가 있다고 했어요
You know Morra says you're psychotic?
그런데도 우리가 만났죠
And yet, here we are.
Yeah.
제 생각을 알아요?
You know what I think?
그 일이 정당한가를 이해를 했죠
I think you know what needs to happen.
저만큼 싸우고 싶은 거죠
And I think you know
you're the one to do it.
그러기에 도움이 조금 필요한 거죠
You just need a little help getting there.
그는 결국 당신의 모든 것을
파괴 할 것이에요, 브라이언
He'll take everything that
means anything to you, Brian.
그저 그가 주장하는 것은
He'll do it and he'll say
세상을 이롭게 하기 위해
본인이 필요하다는 논리죠
it had to happen to make a better world.
제발, 손 좀 놓고 말을 하죠?
Would you take your hands off me, please?
뭔가요?
What is that?
함정이군요?
You set me up?
미안해요, 둘 중에 하나는 살아야죠
I'm sorry. It was you or me.
(gunshot)
(tires screech)
(grunting)
(train horn blares)
잠시만요
Wait, no.
안돼!
(screams): No!
(screams)
모든 카메라 영상은 우리 쪽으로 넘어왔고
SANDS: We got hold of all
the security cam footage.
아무도 너의 얼굴을 몰라
No one saw your face.
그리고...
And...
NYPD에 이미 우리 측 사람들이 있어
we had one of our people from the NYPD
현장에서 나온 총에서 너의 지문을 없앴지
pull that gun with your
prints off the scene.
그러니 전혀 걱정 할 필요가 없어
And there's no trace of you being there.
엉성한 계획치곤
For a botched plan,
결과가 좋네
it went quite well.
자 마셔
Drink that.
제가 죽였어요
I killed her.
DNA도 확인했지
We got a DNA sample.
그녀가 맞아
It was Piper Baird on those tracks.
우리가 일을 재확인 안 할까?
What, you didn't think we'd
double-check your work?
믿든 안 믿든, 난 자네의
Believe it or not, I know exactly
지금 심정을 이해해
what you're feeling right now.
첫 경험 후 내가 무엇을 한지 아나?
Do you know what I did after my first?
4학년 담임에게 전화를 걸었지
I rang my year four teacher.
여자처럼 울어댔지
Cried like I was one of the Sabine women.
그녀에게 왜 전화를 한지 모르겠어
Why her, I don't know.
내 죄를 다 말했지
Practically confessed.
그녀가 신고를 안 한 것이 다행이었지
I'm lucky she didn't turn me in.
어떻게 버티고 사시는...?
How do you live with it...?
이 또한 다 지나가지
All things pass, Brian.
지금 느끼는 그 감정은
The volume of your feelings right now?
다 가라 앉을 꺼야
They'll go down.
어려운 일이지
This is hard.
그러나 세례식 같은 거야
But it's like a baptism.
이제는 한배를 탄 거야
You're an initiate now.
이 제국의 구성원이 되는 거지
You're a part of the real world.
강한 자만이 살아 남는 거야
The strong eat the weak.
늘 그래왔지
Same as it ever was.
(chatting indistinctly)
All right, okay.
다시 한번 늦게 출근했네
You picked the wrong day to come in late.
의원님이 오셔서 모두에게 감사하고 갔어
Senator Morra came by to
thank us all personally.
놓쳐서 아쉽네
Oh, too bad I missed it.
Goatwhore?
Yeah.
고등학교 때 좋아했죠
I liked them in high school.
사람들이 자주 안 오게 하길래
It freaks the people around here out,
내버려 두었어요
so leave it up.
자네에게 질문이 하나 있어
I have a question for you.
지금 답변을 안 해도 돼
You don't have to answer right now.
그러나 이것에 조금 생각을 해준다면
But if you spend some time with it,
자네에게 도움이 될 테야
I think it might help you.
왜 자네는 복용 하기 전의 모습을
Why are you trying so hard to hold on
그렇게도 힘겹게 지키려 들지?
to the person you were before NZT?
그게 접니다
That's who I am.
그걸 필요가 없어
Well, it doesn't have to be.
난 에디 모라를 기억해
I remember Eddie Morra.
형편없는 작가였지
He was a terrible writer.
자기수양에 꽝이고
And he lacked the
self-discipline and awareness
인품 또한 말 다했지
to do anything about it.
그가 다른 자로 되는 것에 기대를 걸었지
I couldn't wait to get rid of
him and become somebody else.
근데 자네는?
But you?
브라이언, 우린 남들과 달라
We're different from other people, Brian.
복용을 한 후에 우리는 신과도 같아
We become more different
with every pill we take.
그런 자신에게서 도망 칠 필요가 없어
You don't have to run from that.
자랑을 해도 돼
You can embrace it.
다른 자신이 되고 싶지 않아요
I don't want to be someone else.
아니 그러고 싶겠지
I think you do.
아직 그걸 안 받아 들였을 뿐이야
You're just not willing to admit it yet.
NZT를 했을 때
You're on NZT.
넌 너 스스로 가진 재량보다
You're above the kind of concerns
더 많은 일을 할 수 있잖아
that you're letting weigh you down.
그러니 받아들이고 더 나아가
Put them down, walk away.
그러면 죄의식 따위는 못 느껴
You'll feel so much lighter.
약속을 하지
I promise.
사실 이해도 어렵더라고요
BRIAN: No, I wasn't followed.
저에게 시키는 대로 했을 뿐인데
I went exactly the way you told me to...
택시 3대, 전철 2량, 카메라에서 사라지는 것
Three cabs, two subways,
avoided every camera
FBI건물에서 여기까지 오는 데
from Federal Plaza to here.
어렵더라고요, 하지만
Not easy to do, by the way,
정말 뉴욕은 안 찍힐 수 없는 도시죠
in the most photographed city in the world.
특히 NZT를 안한 상태라면요
Really not easy to do without NZT.
당신들 생각을 안다...
I know what you're thinking...
"그녀가 살아있네!"
"She's alive!"
다행히야, "그가 그녀를 죽인 줄 알았어"
Also, hopefully, "I thought
for sure he'd killed her."
그 이유는 정말이지...
Because let's be honest...
우리가 노린 자는 당신들이 아니다
You're not the person
we're trying to fool here.
의원도 안 죽일 것이다
I'm not killing Eddie.
아무도 안 죽일 것이다
I'm not killing anybody.
만약 이 전쟁을 계속 하고 싶다면
And if you want to keep up
this war between you guys,
당신 혼자 해요
then that's on you.
그러나 저에게 차선책이 있죠
But in the meantime, I've got an idea.
다행히도 난 전철 앞에 떨어지는 것에
Luckily I know a lot
많은 사실을 알고 있었다
about jumping in front of subway trains,
그리고 그녀 역시 내 계획에 많은 부분
and she, disturbingly, knows a thing or two
생각을 주었고 시체를 훔쳐서
about stealing cadavers and rigging them
지하철 선로 아래에 두자는 것이었다
under subway platforms.
그리고 한 가지 더
There was just one more thing.
그들이 DNA를 검사를 할 것을 알기에
We were fairly certain
Sands would check the DNA
발견 될 사체는 그녀이어야 한다
of the body found at the scene
to be sure it matched Piper.
사체에 그녀의 DNA를 넣을 수 없기에
Since we couldn't put
Piper's DNA into a dead body,
다른 방법을 해보자고 했다...
I suggested we do it the other way around...
시스템 상 사체가 그녀인 것이다
Turn the body into Piper,
at least in the system.
또한 샌즈는 모든 걸 지켜보고 있을 테니
(train horn blares) I also knew Sands
would be watching the whole time,
모든 것은 완벽해야만 했다
so we'd have to make it look perfect.
(train horn blares)
저랑 같이 떠나도 돼요
You should come away with me.
실험실을 준비해두었어요
I have a lab set up.
효소를 만드는 방법을 알아 낼 겁니다
I'm gonna figure out how
that enzyme works, Brian.
모라에게서 자유를 얻을 수 있어요
You can be free of Morra for good.
아직 제가 사랑하는 분들이 계세요
The people I love aren't gone yet.
뉴욕에 말이에요
They're here.
만약 떠난다면
If I leave,
제 스스로 그들을 죽이는 꼴이에요
I-I might as well kill them myself.
제가 충고를 줘도 돼죠?
Can I give you some advice?
의원과의 전쟁을 그만두세요
Just drop this war with Morra.
어떻게 그럴 수 있는 지 생각해보고
Figure out how to make that shot,
본인의 삶을 사세요
and live your life.
아직도 이해를 못했어요
You don't get it yet.
만약 누군가 그를 멈추지 않는다면
If someone doesn't stop Morra,
그 누구도 스스로의 삶이란 것이 없어요
no one's gonna be able to
just "live their life."
브라이언, 세상은 조만간
The whole world's gonna be
다른 곳으로 변할 겁니다
very different, Brian.
그러니 중립적으로 버티긴 힘들어요
You can't play both sides forever.
바로 나라를 벗어나야 해요
You have to leave the country now.
저희가 동의를 한 부분이에요
Like we agreed.
만약 의원이 당신이 살아 있다는 것을 알면
If Morra ever finds out
that you are still alive,
제 인생에 가장 중요한 것은 사라질 겁니다
then everything that means
anything to me is gone.
좋은 가정을 가졌어요
You have a nice family.
다음 번 다시 볼 때는 나은
상황에서 꼭 만나고 싶네요
I hope I get to see you again,
under better circumstances.
♪ When I was done dying,
my conscience regained ♪
♪ So I began my struggle,
a nothingness strained ♪
♪ Out a flash made of time
my new form blasted out ♪
♪ And it startled me so
and I burst out a shout ♪
♪ At which my legs ran frantic
like birds from a nest ♪
♪ And I ran until drained
leaving no choice but rest ♪
♪ So I fell asleep softly
at the edge of a cave ♪
♪ But I should have gone
deeper, but I'm not so brave ♪
♪ And like that I was torn
out and thrown in the sky ♪
♪ And I said all my prayers
because surely I'll die ♪
♪ As I crashed down and smashed
into earth, into dirt ♪
♪ How my skin did explode
leaving only my shirt ♪
♪ But from shirt grew a tree ♪
♪ And then tree grew a fruit, and I... ♪
번역 By 그냥 봐
번역포럼
Synced by emmasan
www.addic7ed.com